Nyrell Leonor

Seattle, WA I (206) 661-2450 I nyrell.leonor2000@gmail.com I www.nyrellcl.com I Github I LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Front-end Developer skilled in creating intuitive, responsive websites and applications using HTML, SASS, and JavaScript/TypeScript, as well as libraries & frameworks such as React and NextJS. Personal experience in branding and have developed my own personal brand through various social media platforms, where I share my personal projects and insights on the latest trends and techniques in front-end development and design.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Designed and developed multiple front-end applications using HTML, CSS, SASS, and JavaScript/TypeScript, with experience in building responsive and dynamic user interfaces using React.js.
- Incorporated mobile-first responsive web design principles, and UI/UX best practices in applications for creating intuitive and engaging user experiences.
- Experience using Git to contribute to multiple codebases for front-end applications.
- Integrated front-end frameworks such as React and NextJS in my development process to enhance the scalability of applications and quality of user interfaces.
- Working knowledge of building APIs and following REST API architecture best practices using Express.js and Node.js.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Logistics Specialist 09/2021 - 12/2022

Frontier Supply Chain Solutions Inc.

- Expanded the company's product database by contributing over 80+ new product codes.
- Cleared over 200+ commercial freight deliveries crossing state borders, with an average of approximately 10 deliveries a day.
- Communicated with commercial drivers and vendors to ensure accurate and timely delivery of goods ensuring clearance that took no longer than 2 days.

Sales Associate 11/2018 - 07/2020

Zara Inc.

- Streamlined check-out process by utilizing efficient floor maintenance techniques resulting in 50% increase in productivity amongst team members.
- Effectively increased productivity by 20% training new employees on daily store tasks and procedures.
- Delivered daily revenue consistently within budget parameters through effective shop organization & sales promotion during peak hours, amplified reach by 25%.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Quote API - TypeScript, REST Architecture, Back-End Development, HTTP Requests, Express.js, Git

- Currently building my own API to deploy and use publicly
- Implemented REST architecture best practices
- Used Express.js to build API efficiently

Website Portfolio

- Designed, developed, & hosted my own website portfolio using HTML, SCSS/SASS, JavaScript, Third Party API's Swiper.js and typed.js.
- Incorporated Google Analytics A4 to monitor and increase website traffic by 200% and steadily increase weekly page views by 15%.

Front-End Projects

- Completed a series of Front-End challenges using various Front-End tools & languages such as HTML, CSS and SCSS/SASS, JavaScript, React.js, and Third Party API's
- Developed interactive and user-friendly web applications using React.js and SCSS/SASS that incorporated UI/UX design principles.

CSS Art - HTML, CSS, SCSS/SASS, Git

- Developed multiple art projects using CSS, to strengthen CSS and design skills
- Used Git for version control and GitHub for continuous deployment

Mock Websites - HTML, SCSS/SASS, JavaScript, React, TailwindCSS, Third Party API, Git

- Developed multiple front-end mock websites using design files and assets to simulate real world front-end practices
- Created documentation for each project to inform users and developers on the development journey

EDUCATION

Shoreline Community College – Shoreline, WA

Purchasing, Procurement/Acquisitions and Contracts Management 09/2021 - 01/2022

Seattle Pacific University— Seattle, WA

Department of Psychology 09/2018 - 01/2019